杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 所以在《了不起的盖茨比》中使用主题的主要好处是
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So the major benefit
of using themes in Gatsby versus just
当你创建一个主题的时候,
doing a site individually is
that when you create a theme,
你可以把这个逻辑用一种可共享的方式打包。
you're able to package up
that logic in a sharable way.
所以在我们今天要创建的主题中，我们要添加对
So in the theme that we're gonna create
today, we're gonna add support for
写文件。
writing up docs.
在这些文档中，我们可能会在多个网站上使用它。
And in those docs,
we might wanna use that in multiple sites.
也许如果你在中介工作，这会成为你工作的共同模式
Maybe if you work in an agency, this is
gonna be a common pattern where you've
有些客户需要相似但稍有不同的东西。
got clients that need similar but
slightly different things.
您可以将所有常见的功能打包到一个主题中，并且
You can package up all the common
functionality into a theme, and
然后以可重复使用的方式分享。
then share that in a reusable way.
使用标准样板文件的一个主要好处是
And a major benefit here over using
a standard boilerplate is that
当您使用一个主题时，该主题是一个 NPM 包。
when you're using a theme,
that theme is an NPM package.
当你使用样板文件时，你就是在克隆回购文件。
When you use a boilerplate,
you're cloning a repo.
一旦你克隆了一个回购，那现在就是你的责任了。
As soon as you clone a repo,
that is now your responsibility.
您已经完全选择了维护该样板文件中的所有代码。
You've fully opted-in to maintaining
all of the code in that boilerplate.
如果事情发生在上游，那么您必须手动导入这些更改。
If things happen upstream, you would have
to then manually import those changes.
您必须查看迁移文档，找出发生了什么变化。
You would have to look at the migration
docs, figure out what changed.
然后，将这些改动移植到样板文件的每个用法中。
And then, port those changes over
into each usage of that boilerplate.
这是一个巨大的痛苦。
That's a huge pain.
如果你有很多网站，如果你正在工作，比如说，一个客户网站，和
And if you've got a lot of sites, if
you're working on, say, a client site, and
他们有一套15种不同的房产,
they've got a suite of
15 different properties,
这样升级的时间投资可不少。
the time investment to do
an upgrade like that is not small.
因此，对于一个主题，它变成了一个包，只是一个已安装的 NPM 包。
So with a theme, it becomes a package,
just an NPM installed package.
所以为了得到上游的更新,
So to get those upstream updates,
你所要做的就是最迟安装 NPM 的主题，然后你就会得到那些更新。
all you have to do is NPM install the
theme at latest and you get those updates.
所以现在，您可以设置类似 dependabot 的东西来自动保存
So now, you can set up something like
dependabot to automatically keep
你的网站最新的任何上游最新的最佳做法是什么。
your sites up to date with whatever
the upstream latest best practice is.
与直接构建主题相比，使用主题的另一个好处是
Another benefit of using themes versus
just building it all out directly is
因为主题是可组合的，你可以把网站分解成小的,
that because themes are composable
you can break down sites into small,
逻辑分组的功能集，处理一件事情真的很好
logically grouped sets of functionality
that handle one thing really well in
一个真正可维护的方式，这样分享就更容易了。
a really maintainable way, which then
makes that sharing much more easy.
如果你建立了一个网站，该网站有一个博客和电子商务
If you built a site, and
that site has a blog and e-commerce and
一个营销页面和一个电子邮件采集表单,
a marketing page and
an email capture form,
这是四种截然不同的工作，如果它们被分解成不同的主题
those are four distinct jobs that if
they were broken into themes, then any
网站，需要一个联系表单，你可以只是下降在联系表单的主题。
site that needs a contact form, you can
just drop in the contact form theme.
任何需要博客的网站，你都可以选择博客主题。
Any site that needs a blog,
you drop in the blog theme.
并且你的网站变得更像乐高积木组装而不是
And your sites become more like
Lego block assembly rather than
查看以前的作品，然后复制粘贴出你需要的部分。
looking at previous work and
copy pasting out the pieces that you need.
所以这会给你所有的好处，作为一个网站建设,
So this is gonna give you all the same
benefits of building it as a site,
但是随着上游升级带来的额外好处以及
but with an added layer of benefits of
upstream updates and the ability to
将较小的代码单元组合在一起的速度和可维护性都要快得多。
compose smaller units of code together
much more quickly and maintainably.
演讲者2: 盖茨比的主题不仅仅是用户界面,
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: So
Gatsby themes is not just about the UI,
其实也是功能性的问题？
it's actually the functionality as well?
贾森 · 兰斯托夫: 盖茨比的主题是 UI 和功能。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Gatsby
themes is UI and functionality.
因此，盖茨比的主题实际上是一个功能完备的盖茨比网站。
So a Gatsby theme is effectively
a fully functioning Gatsby site.
唯一的区别是它接受配置选项和
The only difference is that it
accepts configuration options and
需要作为一个软件包安装，而不是独立运行。
needs to be installed as a package,
as opposed to running standalone.
但是如今很多盖茨比的网站，如果你看看默认的博客主题
But a lot of Gatsby sites these days,
if you look at the default blog theme
它只是一个空文件夹，里面有一个内容文件夹
starter, what it is is just an empty
folder with a content folder for
博客和一个 Gatsby 配置来安装主题。
blogs and
a Gatsby config that installs the theme.
其他的一切都是在主题本身中处理的。
And the rest of everything else in
it is handled in the theme itself.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 你可以在盖茨比的土地上做任何事情，但是
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: It’s anything that
you can do with a Gatsby site, but
以这样一种方式打包，它是可配置的，可重用的，可分享的。
packaged up in such a way that it’s
configurable, reusable, and shareable.
所以从主题到底层的数据操作和
So ranging from theme to
the underlying data manipulation and
模式定制以及在标准站点上可以做的所有事情。
schema customization and all the things
that you would do on a standard site.
说话人3: 插件和主题有什么区别吗
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Is there a difference
between a plugin and a theme, or
一个人能做到另一个人做不到的事？
things that one can do
that the other can't?
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 大多数情况下，没有。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: For the most part, no.
主题的一个主要区别是，当他们使用盖茨比主题标签时,
The one major difference is that themes,
when they use the Gatsby theme tag,
组件隐藏行为，并且他们有一个 Gatsby 配置。
opt-in to component shadowing behavior,
and they have a Gatsby config.
因此，盖茨比主题实际上是一个插件，其中包含一个 Gatsby 配置。
So really, a Gatsby theme is
a plug-in with a Gatsby config in it.
其他的都是没有 Gatsby 配置的插件。
And anything else is a plug-in
without a Gatsby config in it.
这就是主要的区别。
That's the major difference.
然后，命名是必须的，因为盖茨比就是这么认为的
And then, the naming is required because
that's how Gatsby identifies that
一个主题应该用不同的方式处理。
a theme should be handled differently.
演讲者2: 样板文件的概念也会消失
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: So is the concept of
a boilerplate gonna go away pretty much
然后呢？
then?
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 了解盖茨比的世界,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Inside
the Gatsby world,
我认为这个问题不会受到重视。
I would expect that it
will be de emphasized.
我的意思是，我不认为任何东西真的会消失，因为它是一个开放的生态系统。
I mean, I don't think anything ever really
goes away, because it's an open ecosystem.
人们有自己的偏好
People have preferences and
人们会按照自己的方式做事。
people are gonna do things
the way they're gonna do them.
根据我的经验，我已经完全停止使用样板，因为
In my experience, I have completely
stopped using boilerplates because
主题就像样板一样。
themes function as boilerplates.
但是他们给我增加了额外的好处,
But they add an additional layer
of benefits that I, to me,
现在做样板已经没有意义了。
it just doesn't make sense
to do a boilerplate anymore.